Guide to the Mary Coolidge Rentschler Collection 1793-2000 (bulk, 1875-1950) MS 2999
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Mary Rentschler Lowrey addition
  - Subseries III.C. Photoprint Collection
    - Individuals / Groups, circa 1887-1966 (Box MRL-?)
      • Rentschler, Mary C., Helen R. Waldon, Faith A. Witter, Phoebe R. Stanton, Mary R. Lowrey, Susan Witter (on a bike), and a dog, in front of body of water, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1939 (taken by SDW #400-17-9)
      • Rentschler, Mary C., outside 1030 Fifth Avenue, 1962
      • Rentschler, Robert P., July 1887 (print and negative)
      • Schwab, Katie (as a child, wallet size), n.d.
      • Schwab, Mary, 1941
      • Schwab, Mary H., 92nd birthday, 1966 April 15
      • Schwab, Phoebe (as a child, wallet size), n.d.
      • Smith, John, and Helen R. Waldon at the Hamilton, Ohio farm, 1963
      • Smith, John, and Clara Smith at the Hamilton, Ohio farm, c. 1955–1960
      • Stanton, Phoebe R., Mrs. Henry Ford, Mary R. Lowrey, at the Fords' home (oversize), 1938
      • Stanton, Phoebe R., Mary R. Lowrey, with dog (oversize), 1939
      • Waldon, Helen R., in front of train (Sequoia and Sagebrush), 1919
      • Waldon, Helen R. (2 prints by Steichen), 1930s?
      • Waldon, Helen R.—"at Black River Ranch" with a deer [Eliza Gregory], 1932
      • Waldon, Helen R., Mary H. Schwab?—"at Black River Ranch" with a deer [Eliza Gregory] (2 prints), 1932
      • Waldon, Helen R., and 2 unidentified children, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (taken by SDW #400-5-4)
      • Waldon, Helen R., and Mary R. Lowrey, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (taken by SDW #400-5-8)
      • Waldon, Helen R., and 2 unidentified women and a deer "at Black River Ranch" [Eliza Gregory], 1935
      • Waldon, Helen R.—at the Black River Ranch with unidentified man (2 prints), 1937
      • Waldon, Helen R.—at the Black River Ranch with friends, 1937
      • Waldon, Helen R. (oversize), 1940
      • Waldon, Helen R.—at an outdoor special event (launching of a ship?), (2 prints), n.d. (c. 1930s?)
      • Waldon, Helen R., Waldon, Sidney D., and ?, playing a card game, n.d.
      • Waldon, Helen R., Wokie Alsop?—at the Pyramids, Egypt, n.d.
      • Waldon, Helen R., 1960
      • Waldon, Helen R., and Aunt Mary H. Schwab, at latter's 92nd birthday, 1966 April 15
      • Waldon, Helen R., with child lying across her lap, Ohio farm, n.d.
      • Waldon, Sidney D. (print by Steichen), 1930s?
      • Waldon, Sidney D.—with friends outdoors, 1938
      • Waldon, Sidney D. (¾ length portrait), n.d.
      Waldon, Sidney D. (½ length portrait), n.d.
    - Hamilton home, Ohio, 1860s-1943 (Box MRL-?)
      • Façade of Hamilton, Ohio home with Rice family members in front (previous owners of farm), circa 1860s
      • Hamilton home, Ohio (2 oversize prints), n.d. (early images)
      • Hamilton home, Ohio (3 small prints—early images?)
      • Hamilton home, Ohio (early image—house seen from left-hand side), n.d.
      • Hamilton home, Ohio—3 people and a dog on the stoop (HRW?), n.d.
      • Courtyard in front of garage under snow (2 views), Hamilton home, Ohio, n.d.
      • Entrance to garage and laundry, Hamilton home, Ohio, n.d.
      • Hamilton home under snow, 1926 March 17
      • Postcard "Ohio farm—carriage entrance west side of farm" [Eliza Gregory]
      • Person sitting on a post near a ?, n.d.
      • Hamilton home and grounds, Ohio (17 oversize prints), n.d.
      • Hamilton home, Ohio, entrance to service quarter, n.d.
      • Hamilton home, Ohio, "Main carriage entrance at side of house. Do not have picture of front of house," n.d.
      • Hamilton home, Ohio, 1941
      • Hamilton home, Ohio, replanting gardens, inc. Tommy Dorsey (5 prints), 1941
      • Farm buildings under snow, Hamilton, Ohio, 1943
      • Hamilton home, Ohio, n.d.
      • 20 color prints of the safe from the S.S. Maine
      • "John Smith's house, main farm" [Eliza Gregory], n.d.
      • John Smith's house under snow, n.d.
      • Gate to John Smith's house from farm barnyard, n.d.
      • Postcard of "The Cedars" with 2 children holding a baby (looks like Hamilton home), n.d.
      • Postcards (2), one with annotation "our present house, this is the entrance to the kitchen" (porch/north? is now enclosed in glass), c. 1910–1915?
      • Postcard "Greetings from The Hubners"—"lived in Tommy Dorsey's house before the Dorseys moved in" [Eliza Gregory], n.d.
      • Postcard "My dear Gordon. A Merry Christmas, good cheer and success are the wishes to you from the Hubners," n.d.
      Aerial view of Hamilton home, inc. John Smith house, Hubner house, and Tommy Dorsey house, n.d.
    - Little Farm, Hamilton, Ohio, circa 1970s, 1976 (Box MRL-?)
      • Little farm "not smokehouse's 2nd story—suspected station on the underground railroad" [Eliza Gregory]
      • Little farm before remodeling (6 prints pasted onto cardboard), circa 1970s
      • Remodel of Little farm—rear porch, circa 1970s?
      • Remodel of Little farm—kitchen fireplace, circa 1970s
      • Remodel of Little farm—living room, circa 1970s
      • Remodel of Little farm—rear porch at kitchen, circa 1970s
      • Demolition of buildings at Little farm, (26 color snapshots), 1976
    - Hamilton, Ohio, 1913 (Box MRL-?)
      • Rentschler building, Hamilton, Ohio, flood.
    - Locust Valley Home, Long Island, 1933 (Box MRL-?)
      • Locust Vally Home, Long Island (taken by SDW #400-9-15).
    - Sidney D. Waldon photoprints? (Box MRL-?)
  - Subseries III.D. Negative Collection
    Taken by Sidney D. Waldon at Locust Valley, Long Island.
    - {BOX # of #?} (Box MRL-?)
      • Lowrey, Mary R., Stanton, Phoebe R., outdoors, standing on a rug wearing hats and coats (2 views), c. 1930 (#400-3-1, 400-3-8)
      • Lowrey, Mary R.?, in a perambulator (7 views), c. 1930 (#400-3-2, 400-3-3, 400-3-4, 400-3-6, 400-4-2, 400-4-6, 400-4-7)
      • Lowrey, Mary R. picking flowers (4 views), Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (#400-5-11 to 400-5-14)
      • Rentschler, Gordon S., Mary Sweetser, Helen R. Waldon, Mary C. Rentschler, Phoebe R. Stanton, Mary R. Lowrey, Faith A. Witter, Charles Nagel? Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (#400-5-6)
      • Rentschler, Mary C., Helen R. Waldon, Mary Sweetser, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1931 (#400-5-7)
      • Waldon, Helen R. and Mary R. Lowrey, Locust Valley, Long Island, 1932 (#400-5-8)
      Negs added:
      400-3-1 to 400-3-4
      400-3-6
      400-3-8
      400-4-2
      400-4-6
      400-4-7
      400-5-6 to 400-5-8
      400-5-11 to 400-5-24
      400-6-1
      400-6-3 to 400-6-5
      400-7-3
      400-7-6
      400-7-7
      400-9-1
      400-9-2
      400-10-2
      400-14-7
      400-14-8
      400-16-5
      400-17-4 to 400-17-6
      400-17-8
      400-17-9